<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on TachyonVoyager</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on TachyonVoyager</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 20:51:11 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Two extraordinary places to visit on Earth!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/travel/twoplaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 20:51:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/travel/twoplaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a child of science, this blog will enlighten you about two unconventional destinations which can give an unforgettable experience on visit (perhaps a goosebump too!)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gran-sasso-national-laboratorylngs-in-the-italian-alps&#34;&gt;Gran Sasso National Laboratory(LNGS) in the Italian alps&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LNGS is one of Italy’s four National Institutes for Nuclear Physics. LNGS is renowned for its research on particle physics, astrophysics, and other scientific disciplines. Located amidst the beauty of Italian alps and merely 3 to 3.5 hours by road from the city of Rome, this lab is one of the places on earth where the hunt for dark matter is ongoing!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To the elves, volcanoes and whales: at the shores of the Atlantic Ocean and geothermal wonders of Iceland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/travel/iceland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:04:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/travel/iceland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three of us (myself, K &amp;amp; S) eliminated our travel fatigue and woke up quite relaxed on Friday, 26th May 2023. I was still dreaming of the Whales with my eyes open this time, while others got ready for the day. We have planned for whale watching but we haven’t booked a tour yet because tours depends on the weather. Since the weather today isn’t promising, we planned something else for the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To the elves, volcanoes and whales: journey from Germany to Iceland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/psychology/iceland1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 22:37:40 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/psychology/iceland1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was during COVID times that one of my friends suggested the movie Eurovision Song Contest: The Story of Fire Saga. Iceland got into my mind after this movie and I added Iceland to my bucket list. After few months I found a travel partner: one of my ex classmates K. We kick started planning and later on, we got another travel buddy: S. As I was busy and mostly tired during those days and as Chat GPT was getting popular, I tried to generate a three day itinerary with it and later customized it after further research and analysis. I was skeptical about relying entirely on AI for our trip. My travel mates confirmed the itinerary and the three of us decided to spend three days in Iceland. In Iceland I wanted to experience the nature of Iceland, watch the whales, visit the tiny elves houses etc. But now that I know more about this country (with the research part), I want to experience even more of the wonders of this country located in the middle of the Atlantic Ocean in the northern hemisphere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
